<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>javaone on Game On! Adventures with microservices</title><link>/tags/javaone.html</link><description>Recent content in javaone on Game On! Adventures with microservices</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/javaone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Climbing inside your code: A unique look at the game</title><link>/2017/11/02/climbing-inside-your-code.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/11/02/climbing-inside-your-code.html</guid><description>Long long ago, in a land far far away (also known as QCon San Francisco, 2016), I met John Voorhees and Avik Das from Primitive, a small startup building VR tools that allow you to visualize your code in an immersive way.
We were also talking about Game On!, because we're about helping you experiment with new technologies and concepts in a differently immersive way.
They scanned and built a visualization of the core game services, and brought it to JavaOne!</description></item><item><title>Lagom gets in the game at JavaOne 2017</title><link>/2017/10/31/lagom-gets-in-the-game.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/10/31/lagom-gets-in-the-game.html</guid><description>JavaOne was a month ago! No way! Time sure flies.
Our lab with Lightbend was an excellent adventure, complete with the exciting, heart-pounding, last-minute rush to get the materials working end to end. I don't know about you, but that last minute hacking stuff is why I love what I do.
I enjoyed working with the Lightbenders; they're a great team, with solid ideas around how to build reactive applications. What we demonstrated in the lab barely scratched the surface of what you can do with their framework.</description></item><item><title>Headed to JavaOne 2017!</title><link>/2017/09/12/headed-to-javaone.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/09/12/headed-to-javaone.html</guid><description>That's right, Game On! is going back to JavaOne this year!
Frenetic activity has ensued (wow, does this feel familiar), as we prepare for the conference. If you're a frequent visitor, there may be some bumps as we clean things up!
Both a Hands-on Lab and a general session feature the game. Be sure to put them on your schedule!
Introduction to Reactive Systems [HOL7896]
In this two-hour workshop, IBM and Lightbend are teaming up to introduce you to developing reactive microservices on Kubernetes.</description></item><item><title>Game On! at JavaOne 2016</title><link>/2016/09/29/gameon-at-javaone.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2016/09/29/gameon-at-javaone.html</guid><description>Last week was JavaOne in San Francisco and a number of us from the WebSphere Microservices squad (@MarkNSweep, @ebullient, @BarDweller, and @pavittr) were able to go. Game On! made a nice showing, complete with a lab, T-shirts, and prizes.
Read more (with pictures!) at wasdev.net</description></item></channel></rss>