<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>adventure on Game On! Adventures with microservices</title><link>/tags/adventure.html</link><description>Recent content in adventure on Game On! Adventures with microservices</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/adventure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simplified Docker Compose for local development</title><link>/2017/09/22/simplified-docker-compose-for-local-development.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/09/22/simplified-docker-compose-for-local-development.html</guid><description>We now have a special branch in the gameon repository that contains a snapshot of a smooth end-to-end local development flow with docker-compose.
1 2 3 &amp;gt; git clone https://github.com/gameontext/gameon.git &amp;gt; cd gameon &amp;gt; ./go-admin.sh up TA-DA!!
Yes, yes. Kubernetes is next, we promise. But with this revision of the Docker Compose path, we dropped a lot of complexity (bye, Amalgam8!) and created a simplified path for getting started.</description></item><item><title>Swift and Watson Conversation Service</title><link>/2017/04/24/swift-and-watson.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/04/24/swift-and-watson.html</guid><description>Thanks to @jkingoliver, we have a new advanced adventure combining Swift with Watson! This room uses the Watson Conversation Service to create a sandwich shop.
Create a Game On! Room in Swift Integrate Watson Conversation Service Go play!</description></item><item><title>Using JSR-107 Caching in Java-based rooms</title><link>/2017/03/06/jsr107-caching.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/03/06/jsr107-caching.html</guid><description>Caching is one of those awkward bits of function you can totally avoid adding when first creating a bit of code. Everything will work just fine during your initial testing, but worries start to creep in when you start to consider what happens when running at scale: will remote services be invoked too frequently? And what happens to session data when processes are added or removed to accommodate changes in load?</description></item><item><title>What's the weather like?</title><link>/2017/03/05/checking-the-weather.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/03/05/checking-the-weather.html</guid><description>@rstephenrrtx has published a new chronicle relating his experience building a room that checks the weather using IBM Weather Company's REST APIs:
Weather Room (Interacting with REST API service)</description></item><item><title>Using Watson Alchemy Data API to create a News room</title><link>/2017/02/21/watson-news.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/02/21/watson-news.html</guid><description>@bradleyap has published a new chronicle relating his experience using the Watson Alchemy Data API to create a news room:
Making a Watson Alchemy Data News Room</description></item><item><title>Adding items (and interest) to your room</title><link>/2017/02/15/room-items.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/02/15/room-items.html</guid><description>Finally! An adventure dedicated solely to making your room more awesome and interesting. This adventure focuses solely on game protocol and how to enhance your room implementation.
Advanced Adventure for Game On Room Items Go play!</description></item><item><title>Creating a room from scratch</title><link>/2017/02/13/room-from-scratch.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/02/13/room-from-scratch.html</guid><description>Curious how to write your own room from scratch without a fork/clone? We've got your back, intrepid explorer, behold this adventure written just for you:
Advanced Adventure for room creation from scratch Go play!</description></item></channel></rss>